<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on DAHRSE-Midlands</title>
    <link>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on DAHRSE-Midlands</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Co-Creating DAHRSE Midlands: Vision, Voices, and Next Steps</title>
      <link>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/co-creating-dahrse-midlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/co-creating-dahrse-midlands/</guid>
      <description>On 5th November 2025, the Digital Arts and Humanities Research Software Engineers Midlands (DAHRSE Midlands) community gathered online for its first meeting. The theme “Co-Creating DAHRSE Midlands: Vision, Voices, and Next Steps” was all about collaboration, inclusivity, and building momentum for Digital Arts and Humanities Research Software Engineering in the Midlands.
The DAHRSE Midlands community is growing as a collaborative space for Digital Arts and Humanities Research Software Engineers (RSEs) across the region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Short Talks – DAHRSE-Midlands 2025 (5 Nov, University of Warwick)</title>
      <link>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/dahrse-midlands-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/dahrse-midlands-2025/</guid>
      <description>DAHRSE-Midlands 2025 will take place at the University of Warwick. DAHRSE Midlands 2025 will take place on Wednesday 5th November 2025.
For more detials on submitting a talk, please go to DAHRSE Midlands 2025 page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prospects of Digital Arts and Humanities Research Software Engineers in the Midlands for AHRC Doctoral Landscape Awards</title>
      <link>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/prospects-dahrse-midlands-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/prospects-dahrse-midlands-2025/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, the integration of digital technologies into the arts and humanities has opened new avenues for research and innovation. One of the key drivers of this transformation is the emergence of Digital Arts and Humanities Research Software Engineers (DAHRSEs). These professionals possess a unique blend of technical expertise and a deep understanding of the arts and humanities, making them invaluable assets in the research landscape.
The Role of DAHRSE in the Midlands The Midlands region of England, known for its rich cultural heritage and vibrant academic community, is an ideal setting for the growth of DAHRSE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAHRSE-Midlands at the RSE Midlands 2025</title>
      <link>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/rse-midlands-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 18:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/rse-midlands-2025/</guid>
      <description>DAHRSE-Midlands will participate in the Software Sustainability Institute (SSI) session at the RSE Midlands 2025 Conference. RSE Midlands 2025 will take place on Monday 7th April 2025 at The Exchange, hosted by the University of Birmingham&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Research Computing team.
For more detials, please go to RSE Midlands Website - https://rse-midlands.github.io.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSI Inaugural Meeting: Announcing New Fellows on January 30, 2025</title>
      <link>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/ssi-inaugural-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 18:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/ssi-inaugural-meeting/</guid>
      <description>DAHRSE-Midlands awarded Software Sustainability Institute (SSI) Fellowship. The inaugural meeting for announcing the fellowship will take place on Thursday 30 January 14:00-17:00 (GMT).
The fellowship will help foster collaboration and innovation among like-minded professionals. The announcement post is at the following SSI webpage Introducing the 2025 Fellowship Cohort: Insights and Celebrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Hugo Site Like DAHRSE-Midlands Website</title>
      <link>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/setting-up-a-hugo-site-like-dahrse-midlands-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 15:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dahrse-midlands.github.io/posts/setting-up-a-hugo-site-like-dahrse-midlands-website/</guid>
      <description>Setting up a Hugo site with the Box template on GitHub Pages using GitHub Codespaces and a new repository can streamline your web development process. This guide walks you through the necessary steps, from installing Hugo in VSCode to creating and configuring your repositories, and finally deploying your site. By following these instructions, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a fully functional Hugo site hosted on GitHub Pages, just like the DAHRSE-Midlands website.
Assumptions  Visual Studio Code (VSCode) is already installed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
